thewhiskeywash.com 2019-09-22

# Privacy Policy - The Whiskey Wash

_Last updated: 6/22/18_

Thank you for choosing to connect with The Whiskey Wash. When you visit our website and use our services, you trust us with your personal information. We are committed to maintaining that trust and confidence and protecting your personal information and right to privacy.

This Privacy Policy applies to all information collected through our website, www.TheWhiskeyWash.com (our “Site”) and/or any related services, sales, marketing, or events. In this Privacy Policy, we want to explain to you clearly what personal information we collect, how we use it, and what rights you have in relation to it. We hope you take some time to read it carefully as it will help you make informed decisions about sharing your personal information with us. If there are any terms in this Privacy Policy that you do not agree with, please discontinue use of our Site and our services.

1\. **WHAT PERSONAL INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT?**

1.1. We may collect personal information that you provide to us. The personal information that we collect depends on the context of your interactions with us and our Site, the choices you make, and the products and features you use.

1.2. The personal information we collect may include:

a. Your first and last name, email address, mailing address, phone number, and other similar contact information;

b. Passwords, password hints, and similar security information used for authentication and account access;

c. Your online browsing activity on our Site;

d. When you make a purchase, information necessary to process your payment, such as your credit card number and the security code associated with your credit card; and

e. When you register using social media, your account details, like your Facebook, Twitter, or other social media account. If you choose to register in this way, we will collect the information described in Section 5 (“How Do We Handle Your Social Logins?”) below. We may need to collect additional information for the purposes set out in this Policy.

1.3. Some of the above personal information, such as your IP address and browser and device characteristics, is collected automatically when you visit our Site. When someone visits our Site, for example, we use a third-party service, Google Analytics, to collect information such as your operating system, language preferences, referring URLs, device name, country, location, information about how and when you use our Site, and other technical information. This information is primarily needed to maintain the security and operation of our Site and for our internal analytics and reporting purposes. It is processed only in a way that does not identify anyone. We do not make, and do not allow Google to make, any attempt to find out the identities of our visitors.

1.4. Other information, some of which may reveal your specific identity, may be collected through similar technologies when you access our Site on your mobile device. We may collect:

a. Geo–Location Information. We may request access or permission to and track location–based information from your mobile device, either continuously or while you use our Site, to provide location–based services. If you wish to change our access or permissions, you may do so in your device’s settings.

b. Mobile Device Access. We may request access or permission to certain features from your mobile device, including your device’s calendar, SMS messages, and other features. If you wish to change our access or permissions, you may do so in your device’s settings.

c. Push Notifications. We may request to send you push notifications regarding your account or our Site. If you wish to opt–out from receiving these types of communications, you may turn them off in your device’s settings.

d. Information Collected from Other Sources. We may collect limited information from public databases, marketing partners, social media platforms, and other outside sources, such as public databases, joint marketing partners, social media platforms such as Facebook, and from other sources. Examples of information we may receive from other sources include: social media profile information (your name, gender, birthday, email, current city, state, and country, user identification numbers for your contacts, your profile picture URL, and any other information that you choose to make public); marketing leads, search results, and links, including paid listings such as sponsored links.

 **2\. DO WE USE COOKIES AND OTHER TRACKING TECHNOLOGIES?**

2.1. What are cookies? Cookies are small pieces of text sent by your web browser by a website you visit. A cookie file is stored in your web browser and allows our Site to recognize you and make your next visit easier and our Site more useful to you.

2.2. How we use cookies. When you use and access our Site, we may place a number of cookies files in your web browser. We use cookies to to authenticate users and prevent fraudulent use of user accounts, enable certain functions of our Site, store your preferences, provide analytics, and enable delivery of advertising.

2.3. What are your choices regarding cookies? Most web browsers allow you to delete or refuse cookies. If you would like to do so, please visit the help pages of your web browser. Please note that if you delete cookies or refuse to accept them, you might not be able to use all of the features we offer or store your preferences, and some of our pages might not display properly.

2.4. Where can you find more information about cookies? You can learn more about cookies and opt-out of interest-based advertising by advertisers on our Site at: the following third-party websites:

a. Digital Advertising Alliance: <https://www.aboutads.info/choices/>

b. Network Advertising Initiative: <https://www.networkadvertising.org/>

**3\. HOW DO WE USE YOUR INFORMATION?**

3.1. We may use the personal information we collect or receive:

a. To provide goods and services to you. We may use your personal information to evaluate and improve our Site, products, services, marketing, and your experience;

b. To better understand your needs. We may use your personal information to request feedback and to contact you about your use of our Site.

c. To manage registered account(s) that you hold with us. We may use your personal information including information you may allow us to collect from social media accounts such as your Google or Facebook account to create your account with us and allow you to log on to our Site. Please see Section 5 (“How do We Handle your Social Logins?”) below for more information.

d. To verify your identity. We may use your personal information as part of our efforts to keep our Site safe and secure from crime and fraud.

e. To manage customer service interactions with you. We may use your personal information to fulfill and manager orders and to send administrative information, product, service, and new feature information, and/or information about changes to our terms, conditions, and policies.

f. Where we have a legal right or duty to use or disclose your information. We may use your personal information to respond to legal requests and prevent harm for legal reasons. If, for example, we receive a subpoena or other legal request in relation to an investigation by a public authority or in a legal dispute, we may need to inspect the information we hold to determine how to respond. We may also use your personal information to enforce our terms, conditions, and policies for business purposes.

g. To contact you about promotional offers and products and services that we think may interest you. With your consent, we may use your personal information to develop and display content, advertising, and other communications tailored to your interests and/or location and to measure their effectiveness. You can opt–out of our marketing emails at any time. Please see Section 10 (“What are Your Privacy Rights”) below for more information.

 **4\. WILL YOUR INFORMATION BE SHARED WITH ANYONE?**

4.1. We share and disclose your information only in the following situations:

a. Compliance with laws. We may disclose your personal information where we are legally required to do so. This may occur if we are required to comply with applicable law, judicial proceedings, court orders, legal process, or in response to public authorities to meet national security or law-enforcement requirements.

b. Vital interests and legal rights. We may disclose your personal information where we reasonably believe it is necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action on potential violations of our policies, potential threats to the safety of any person, suspected fraud or other illegal activity, or as evidence in litigation in which we are involved.

c. Third-party service providers. We may disclose your personal information to third-party vendors, service providers, contractors, or agents with whom we work to deliver the best possible online experience. This may occur, for example, to process payments, analyze and track data, determine the popularity of certain content, enable e-mail delivery or hosting services, or improve customer service efforts. Unless described elsewhere in this Privacy Policy, we will not share, sell, rent, or trade any of your personal information with third parties for their promotional purposes. We encourage you to familiarize yourself with the privacy policies of technology providers who may assist us by following the links below:

i. <https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en>

ii. <https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/>

d. Business transfers. We may disclose your personal information in connection with any transfer of our company or its assets to another company. This may occur in connection with a merger, sale, financing, or acquisition of all or a portion of our business, or with related negotiations.

e. With your consent. We may disclose your personal information for any other purpose with your consent.

 **5\. HOW DO WE HANDLE YOUR SOCIAL LOGINS?**

5.1. If you choose to register or log into our Site using a social media account, we may have access to certain information about you.

5.2. Our Site allows you to register and log in using your third party social media account details, such as your Facebook or Twitter logins. Where you choose to do this, we will receive certain profile information about you from your social media provider. The profile information we receive may vary depending on the social media provider concerned but will often include your name, email address, friends list, profile picture, and other information you choose to make public.

5.3. We will use the information we receive only for the purposes that are described in this Privacy Policy. We do not control other uses of your personal information by your third-party social media provider, and we are not responsible for their uses of your personal information. We recommend that you review their privacy policies to understand how they collect, use, and share your personal information and how you can set your privacy preferences on their sites and apps.

 **6\. WHAT IS OUR POSITION ON THIRD-PARTY ADVERTISING?**

6.1. We are not responsible for the safety of any information that you share with third-party providers who may advertise on our Site.

6.2. Our Site may contain advertisements from third parties that may link to other websites, online services, or mobile applications. We are not responsible for the content or privacy and security practices of any third parties, including other websites, online services, or mobile applications that may be linked to or from our Site. We cannot guarantee the safety and privacy of information that you provide to any third parties, and this Privacy Policy does not apply to any information that third parties may collect from you. We recommend that you review the privacy policies of such third parties and contact them directly to respond to any questions that you may have about their privacy practices.

 **7\. HOW LONG DO WE KEEP YOUR INFORMATION?**

7.1. We keep your personal information for only as long as is necessary for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy, unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law (such as tax, accounting, or other legal requirements) as described in Section 10 (“What are Your Privacy Rights?”). When we have no ongoing legitimate business need to process your personal information, we will either delete or anonymize it, or, if this is not possible (for example, because your personal information has been stored in backup archives), then we will securely store your personal information and isolate it from any further processing until deletion is possible.

 **8\. HOW DO WE KEEP YOUR INFORMATION SAFE?**  
8.1. We have implemented appropriate technical and organizational security measures to protect the security of any personal information we process. We cannot, however, guarantee that the Internet is 100% secure. Please remember that although we will do our best to protect your personal information, transmission of personal information to and from our Site is at your own risk. We recommend that you access our Site and use our services only within a secure environment.

 **9\. DO WE COLLECT INFORMATION FROM MINORS?**

9.1. We do not knowingly solicit information from or market to children under 18 years of age. If we learn that personal information from users less than 18 years of age has been collected, we will deactivate any account involved and take reasonable measures to properly delete such information from our records. If you become aware of any information we may have collected from any child under age 18, please contact us using the details below in Section 13 (“How Can You Contact Us About This Policy?”).

9.2. By using our Site, you represent that you are at least 18 years of age or that you are the parent or guardian of such a minor and consent to such minor dependent’s use of our Site. We do not permit anyone under the age of 21 to receive our e-mails.

 **10\. WHAT ARE YOUR PRIVACY RIGHTS?**

10.1. You may review, change, or terminate your account at any time.

10.2. If you are resident in the European Economic Area and you believe we are unlawfully processing your personal information, you also have the right to complain to your local data protection supervisory authority. You can find their contact details here: https://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protecton/bodies/authorities/index_en.htm.

10.3. Account Information. If you would at any time like to review or change the information in your account or terminate your account, you can:

a. Log into your account settings and update your user account; or

b. Contact us using the details below in Section 13 (“How Can You Contact Us About This Policy?”).

10.4. Upon your request to terminate your account, we will deactivate or delete your account and personal information from our active databases. Some information, however, may be retained in our files to prevent fraud, investigate and resolve problems, enforce our Terms of Use, or comply with legal requirements.

10.5. Opting Out of E-Mail Marketing. You may opt-out of e-mail marketing when you register an account, access your account settings, and update your preferences. You may also unsubscribe from our marketing e-mail list at any time by clicking on the unsubscribe link in the e-mails that we send or by contacting us using the details below in Section 13 (“How Can You Contact Us About This Policy?”). We will then remove you from our marketing e-mail list. We will, however, still need to send you service-related e-mails necessary for the administration and use of your account.

 **11\. DO CALIFORNIA RESIDENTS HAVE SPECIFIC PRIVACY RIGHTS?**

11.1. Notice to California Residents – Your California Privacy Rights. Under California Civil Code Section 1798.83 (the “Shine the Light” law), users who are California residents may request certain information about our disclosure of personal information during the prior calendar year to third parties for their direct marketing purposes.

11.2. In addition, under California Business and Professions Code Section 22581, California residents under age 18 who are registered users of online sites, services, or applications may request and obtain removal of content or information they have publicly posted. The request must include a detailed description of the specific content or information to be removed. Please be aware that a request does not guarantee complete removal of content or information posted online, and that the law may not permit or require removal in certain circumstances.

11.3. If you are a California resident and would like to make such a request, please submit your request in writing to us using the details below in Section 13 (“How Can You Contact Us About This Policy?”).

 **12\. DO WE UPDATE THIS PRIVACY POLICY?**

12.1. We will update this policy as necessary to comply with relevant laws. The updated version will be indicated by an updated “Revised” date, and the updated version will be effective as soon as it is accessible. If we make material changes to this Privacy Policy, we may notify you either by prominently posting a notice of such changes or by directly sending you a notification. We encourage you to review this Privacy Policy frequently to be informed of how we protect and use your personal information.

 **13\. HOW CAN YOU CONTACT US ABOUT THIS PRIVACY POLICY?**

13.1. If you have questions or comments about this policy, please contact our Data Protection Officer (“DPO”) by email at Privacy@TheWhiskeyWash.com or phone at (503) 683-3765. You may also write to us at The Whiskey Wash LLC., ATTN: Data Protection Officer, 1631 NE Broadway, Suite 109, Portland, OR 97232.
